Serge Diaghilev/Serge Lifar Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- I. Printed Music Material, 1750-1950 (Box 1-67)
  - A. General (Box 1-65)
    - Holländer, Friedrich
      - Loin de toi. [=Wie hab'ich nur leben können Dich?] Paris: F. Salabert, 1933., Parts for: piano/conductor (4 p.); vn I/conductor (reduced score) (3 p.) (2 copies); vn II, vla, vc, cb, fl, ob, cl I, sax I (alto), sax II (tenor), sax III (alto), tpt I, tpt II, tbn, perc, banjo (2 p. each); Plate no. E.A.S.8642.; parts contain vocal line indications; "Valse anglaise du film Moi et l'Impératrice."; Language note: French (Box-folder 31/11)
      - Qui j'aime. [=Ich weiss nicht zu wem ich gehöre.] Paris: F. Salabert, 1932., Parts for: piano/conductor (4 p.); vn I/ conductor (2 p.) (2 copies); vn II, vla, vc, cb, fl, ob, cl I, sax I (alto), sax II (tenor), sax III (alto), tpt I, tpt II, tbn, perc, banjo (2 p. each); Plate no. E.A.S.7350.; Language note: French; parts contain vocal line indications; "Valse anglaise du film Tumultes." (Box-folder 31/12)
    - Howard, Samuel
      - The Amorous Goddess See: I.B. Collections, Box 1 (S/62), p. 67
    - d'Indy, Vincent
      - Attendez-moi sous l'Orme. Paris: Enoch, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 106 p.; Plate no. E. & C.807.; Contains annotations in pencil on front cover.; Language note: French (Box-folder 31/13)
    - Inghelbrecht, Désiré Émile
      - Le diable dans le beffroi. Paris: Heugel, 1927., Reduction for solo piano; score; 76 p.; Plate no. 29551. (Box-folder 31/14)
    - Kalinnikov, Vasiliĭ Sergeevich
      - Chanson triste. Moscow: P. Jurgenson, n.d., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 26077. (Box-folder 31/15)
    - Kéler, Béla
      - Lustspiel-Ouverture, op. 73. Berlin: Edition Europa, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. Ed.771 Er.; Composer also known by the name: Keler, Albert von (Box-folder 31/16)
    - Kool, Jaap
      - Der Leierkasten. Vienna: Universal, 1925., Reduction by K. Mengelberg for solo piano; score; 44 p.; Plate no. U.E.8295. (Box-folder 31/17)
    - Kuzmin, Mikhaĭl
      - Aleksandriĭskie pesni, v. 1. Moscow: Gosudarstvennoe muzykal'noe izdatel'stvo, 1921., Voice and piano; score; 23 p.; Plate no. G.M.776 (477, 778 through 781) I.M.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 31/18)
    - Labadie, H.
      - Mia cara See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
    - Lalo, Édouard
      - Divertissement. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 23 p.; Plate no. H.et Cie.20223. (Box-folder 31/19)
      - Pastorale et scherzo alla Pulcinella, op. 8. Paris: Costallat, n.d., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 3 p.; 10 p.; Plate no. R.10667. (Box-folder 31/20)
      - Il re d'Ys. [=Le roi d'Ys.] Milan: E. Sonzogno, 1890., Piano-vocal score; 231 p.; Plate no. G.H. & Cie.1745, .1939.; Published also by: G. Hartmann in Paris, 1890; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 32/1)
    - Lama, Gaetano
      - Pallida mimosa. Naples: F. Feola, 1921., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 1745.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 32/2)
    - Laskowsky, J.
      - Valse See: Glinka, Mikhaĭl. Sobranie muzykal'nykh pies, Box 66, Folder 9
    - Lassen, Eduard
      - Pominal'nyĭ den', op. 85, no. 3. Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', 1891., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.5803 G.; Language note: Russian; Language note: German (Box-folder 32/3)
    - Le Borne, Fernand
      - Judith, op. 71. Paris: Deiss & Crépin, 1922., Full score; 103 p.; Plate no. D. & C.5625. (Box-folder 32/4)
    - Lecocq, [Alexandre] Charles
      - Le cygne. Paris: Heugel, 1899., Reduction for solo piano; score; 87 p.; Plate no. H. & Cie.19760. (Box-folder 32/5)
    - Lehár, Franz
      - Tsyganskaia liubov' [=Gypsy Love]: Waltz. Moscow: S.IA. IAmbor, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 4 p.; Composer also known by the name: Legar, F. (Box-folder 32/6)
      - Veselaia vdova [=The Merry Widow.]: Waltz. Moscow: S.IA. IAmbor, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 4 p.; Composer also known by the name: Legar, F. (Box-folder 32/7)
    - Liadov, Anatoliĭ Konstantinovich
      - Arabesques, op. 4, no. 1. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.L.13698. (Box-folder 32/8)
      - Arabesques, op. 4, no. 2. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. A.L.13699. (Box-folder 32/9)
      - Arabesques, op. 4, no. 3. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.L.13700. (Box-folder 32/10)
      - Arabesques, op. 4, no. 4. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. A.L.13701. (Box-folder 32/11)
      - Bagatelle, op. 30. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1892., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 524. (Box-folder 32/12)
      - Trois bagatelles, op. 53. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1903., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 2415. (Box-folder 32/13)
      - Biroulki, op. 2. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 27 p.; Plate no. A.L.8756. (Box-folder 32/14)
      - Trois canons, op. 34. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1894., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 935. (Box-folder 32/15)
      - Etiud i kantsonetta, op. 48. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1899., Solo piano; score; 10 p.; Plate no. 2074 through 2076. (Box-folder 32/16)
      - Etiud i 3 preliudii, op. 40. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1897., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 1455 through 1457. (Box-folder 32/17)
      - Fantaziia na russkuiu piesniu Vozlie riechki, vozlie mostu. Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', n.d., Arranged for piano, four hands; score; 17 p.; Plate no. A.2162 G. (Box-folder 32/18)
      - Idilliia, op. 25. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1891., Solo piano; score; 10 p.; Plate no. 413. (Box-folder 32/19)
      - Le lac enchanté, op. 62. [=Volshebnoe ozero.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1909., Arranged by B. Kalafati for piano, four hands; 11 p.; Plate no. 2849. (Box-folder 32/20)
      - Mazurka, op. 38. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1896., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 1350. (Box-folder 32/21)
      - Deux mazurkas, op. 15. Paris: J. Hamelle, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. J.2745 H. (Box-folder 32/22)
      - 2 morceaux, op. 24. [=2 p'esy.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1890., Solo piano; score; 19 p.; Plate no. 295.339 through 295.340. (Box-folder 32/23)
      - Deux morceaux, op. 31. [=2 p'esy.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1893., Solo piano; score; 13 p.; Plate no. 773.774, 773.775. (Box-folder 32/24)
      - Trois morceaux, op. 10, no. 1: Prélude. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.L.13520. (Box-folder 32/25)
      - Trois morceaux, op. 10, no. 2: Mazurka, C major. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. A.L.13521. (Box-folder 32/26)
      - Trois morceaux, op. 10, no. 3: Mazurka, D major. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.L.13522. (Box-folder 32/27)
      - Trois morceaux, op. 57. [=Tri p'esy.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1906., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 2596.2597 through 2596.2599. (Box-folder 33/1)
      - Quatre morceaux, op. 64. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1910., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 2797. (Box-folder 33/2)
      - Six morceaux. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 23 p.; Plate no. A.L.8755. (Box-folder 33/3)
      - 3 morceaux de ballet, op. 52. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1901., Solo piano; score; 1 p.; incomplete: cover page, p. 3-4 only; Plate no. 2340, 2341. (Box-folder 33/4)
      - Novelette, op. 20. [=Novinka.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1889., Solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 176. (Box-folder 33/5)
      - Petite valse, op. 26. Leipzig: Bosworth, 1908., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. B. & Co. 10867. (Box-folder 33/6)
      - Deux préludes et mazurka, op. 42. [=2 preliudii i mazurka.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1898., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 1694.1695 through 1694.1697. (Box-folder 33/7)
      - 3 préludes, op. 27. [=3 preliudii.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1891., Solo piano; score; 12 p.; Plate no. 442.443 through 442.445. (Box-folder 33/8)
      - 3 préludes, op. 36. [=3 préludes.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1895., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 1266. (Box-folder 33/9)
      - Quatre préludes, op. 13. St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', n.d., Solo piano; score; 13 p.; Plate no. 2024 (a) through (d). (Box-folder 33/10)
      - Quatre préludes, op. 39. [=4 preliudii.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1896., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 1351.1352 through 1351.1355. (Box-folder 33/11)
      - Quatre préludes, op. 46. [=4 preliudii.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1899., Solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 1983. (Box-folder 33/12)
      - Une tabatière à musique, op. 32. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1893., Solo piano; score; 6 p.; Plate no. 776. (Box-folder 33/13)
      - Valse, op. 9, no. 1. [=Two pieces: Valse.] Leipzig: Bosworth, 1897., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. B. & Co. 1253. (Box-folder 33/14)
      - Variations sur un thème populaire polonais, op. 51. [=Variatsii.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1901., Solo piano; score; 18 p.; Plate no. 2288. (Box-folder 33/15)
    - Lipnitzki, Boris
      - Les aveugles. [S.l.]: Boris Lipnitzki, n.d., Reduction for solo piano; score; 20 p. (Box-folder 33/16)
    - Liszt, Franz
      - Le rossignol. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1917., Arranged by A. Aliab'ev for piano solo; score; 6 p.; Plate no. 06568. (Box-folder 33/17)
    - Locatelli, Pietro Antonio
      - Sonate, op. 6, G major: 1. Largo-allemande. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 1 p.; 2 p.; Also published Paris: B. Roudanez, n.d.; Plate no. S.R.et Cie.179. (Box-folder 33/18)
      - Sonate, op. 6, G major: 2. Sicilienne. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 1 p.; 2 p.; Also published Paris: B. Roudanez, n.d.; Plate no. S.R.et Cie.73. (Box-folder 33/19)
      - Sonate, op. 6, G major: 3. Gigue. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 1 p.; 2 p.; Also published Paris: B. Roudanez, n.d.; Plate no. S.R.et Cie.180. (Box-folder 33/20)
    - Loucheur, Raymond
      - Hop-Frog. [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Reduction for solo piano; score; 71 p. (Box-folder 33/21)
    - L'vov, A.
      - Dukhovno-muzykal'nyia. [=Sacred musical works.] St. Petersburg: [s.n.], n.d., Mixed chorus (SATB) and piano; score; 238 p.; Plate no. 6268 through 6354 (even numbers only).; Contains holograph inscription in pencil inside front cover: "vieux chants d'église russe" ("old songs of the Russian church").; Language note: Russian; Note: A. [Alekseĭ Fëdorovich (?)] L'vov (Box-folder S/46)
    - Lynde, L. L.
      - One day, one night. Paris: F. Salabert, 1918., Arranged for solo piano by F. Salabert; score; 7 p.; Plate no. E.A.S.937. (Box-folder 33/22)
    - Malderen, Édouard van
      - Le tango du rêve. Paris: L. Maillochon, 1919., Solo piano; score; 2 p.; Plate no. W.S.124. (Box-folder 33/23)
    - Malipiero, Gian Francesco
      - La mascherata delle principesse prigioniere. [=La mascarade des prin-cesses captives.] London: J. & W. Chester, 1919., Reduction for piano, four hands; score; 46 p.; Plate no. J. & W.C.2908. (Box-folder 33/24)
    - Marchetti, F. D.
      - Fascination See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
    - Margis, Alfred
      - La châtelaine See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
      - Pourquoi ne pas m'aimer See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68
      - Premier printemps See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
    - Marie, William
      - Caroles du moyen-âge. Paris: G. Legouix, n.d., Solo piano; score; 20 p.; Plate no. G.L.G.1462. (Box-folder 33/25)
      - Contredanses du directoire. Paris: G. Legouix, n.d., Solo piano; score; 12 p.; Plate no. G.L.G.1398. (Box-folder 33/26)
      - Danses d'almées, op. 35: Chanson orientale. Paris: G. Legouix, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. G.L.G.1228. (Box-folder 33/27)
      - Danses d'almées, op. 35: Pas des voiles. Paris: G. Legouix, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. G.L.G.1229. (Box-folder 33/28)
      - Danses anciennes. Paris: G. Legouix, n.d., Solo piano; score; 15 p.; Plate no. 1396, 1397, 1437, 1362. (Box-folder 33/29)
      - Danses du grand siècle. Paris: G. Legouix, n.d., Solo piano; score; 18 p.; Plate no. G.L.G.1437. (Box-folder 33/30)
      - Danses romantiques. Paris: G. Legouix, n.d., Solo piano; score; 13 p. (Box-folder 33/31)
    - Marinier, Paul
      - Bonsoir Madame la lune; D'elle à lui See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
    - Mariotte, Antoine
      - Salomé. Paris: Enoch, 1910., Piano-vocal score; 231 p.; Plate no. E. & C.7095.; Language note: French (Box-folder 34/1)
    - Marks, Gerald See: Fields, Buddy and Marks, Gerald
    - Marsden, Evan
      - From a Russian village. London: J.H. Larway, 1926., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. L.2829. (Box-folder 34/2)
      - From a Russian village. London: J.H. Larway, 1926., Arranged by E. Mareo for small orchestra; parts for: piano/conductor (condensed score) (7 p.); vn I (2 copies, 3 p. each); vn II, vla, vc, cb, fl, ob (2 p. each); cl (4 p.); bn, hn (2 p. each); tpt (3. p); tbn (2 p.); timp (1 p.); perc (2 p.); harmonium (4 p.).; 30 p.; Plate no. L.2832. (Box-folder 34/3)
    - Martini, Giovanni Battista
      - Gavotte des moutons. [Sonata no. 12.] Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 1011. (Box-folder 34/4)
    - Martini, Jean Paul Égide
      - Plaisir d'amour. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 1019. (Box-folder 34/5)
    - Massenet, Jules Émile Frédéric
      - Pensée d'automne See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
      - Le roman d'Arlequin. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. H.et Cie 9200. (Box-folder 34/6)
      - Scènes de bal, op. 17. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Arranged by G. Bizet for solo piano; score; 15 p.; Plate no. H.et Cie 9459/G.H.844. (Box-folder 34/7)
    - Méhul, Étienne Nicolas
      - Une folie. [S.l.]: J. André, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 95 p.; Plate no. 1823.; Contains annotations in pencil.; Language note: French; Language note: German (Box-folder S/25)
      - L'irato. [=L'emporté.] Paris: Mme. V. Launer, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 116 p.; Plate no. Ve 3311.; Language note: French (Box-folder 34/8)
      - Ouverture burlesque. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Full score; 9 p.; Plate no. D.S. & Cie 2065.; Laid in: copyist's arrangement for solo piano, 4 p., in ink. (Box-folder 34/9)
      - Ouverture burlesque. Paris: Durand & Schoenewerke, n.d., Parts for: vn (2 copies); "mirlitons" I, II, III (2 p. each); tpt, [perc:] snare drum, triangle, "crécelle" (1 p. each).; Plate no. D.S. & Cie 2065.; Contains performance indications in pencil. (Box-folder 34/10)
      - Der Schatzgräber. [=Le trésor supposé.] [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Piano-vocal score; 65 p.; Plate no. 258 through 266.; Language note: German (Box-folder 34/11)
    - Melfi, A. Mario.
      - Pourquoi mentir. Paris: Éditions espagnoles J. Garzón, n.d., Arranged for small orchestra; parts for: piano/accordion (3 p.); vn (2 p.); vc-cb, tpt-sax (alto), perc (1 p. each).; Plate no. 1780.; On verso of each part: corresponding instrumental part for Espinosa, L., Titi. All Melfi material is included with the Espinosa material (Box 22, Folder 7). (Box-folder 22/7)
    - Mendelssohn [-Bartholdy], Felix
      - Klavierwerke, v. 4: Sämmtliche Leider ohne Worte; Kinderstücke, op. 72. Leipzig: Steingräber, n.d., Solo piano; score; 86 p.; Plate no. 57. (Box-folder 34/12)
    - Messager, André Charles Prosper
      - Isoline. Paris: Enoch, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 229 p.; Plate no. E.F. & C.1545.; Language note: French (Box-folder 34/13)
    - Migot, Georges
      - Le livre de danceries. Paris: A. Leduc, 1930., Flute/violin, violin, piano; parts for: fl/vn, vn; piano score; 10 p.; 10 p.; 37 p.; Plate no. A.L.17704.; Laid in: photoreproduced copy of typescript, 3 p., in French. (Box-folder 35/1)
    - Milhaud, Darius
      - Le train bleu, op. 84. Paris: Heugel, 1924., Reduction for solo piano; score; 65 p.; Plate no. H.28728.; Contains holograph inscription from the composer to Diaghilev on inside front cover page. (Box-folder 35/2)
    - Missa, Edmond
      - L'éventail See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68
    - Monteverdi, Claudio
      - Orfeo. Paris: Schola Cantorum, 1905., Piano-vocal score; 73 p.; Plate no. S.1800.C.; Language note: French (Box-folder 35/3)
    - Morny, Charles Auguste and Jacques Offenbach
      - Monsieur Choufleuri restera chez lui le.... Paris: Heugel, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 70 p.; Plate no. H.4608.; Language note: French; Composer also known by the name: Saint-Rémy (Box-folder 55/4)
    - Mosolov, Aleksandr Vasil'evich
      - Sonata, no. 1, op. 3. Moscow: Muzykal'nyĭ sektor gosudarstvennoe izdatel'stva, 1926., Solo piano; score; 15 p.; Plate no. M.7337.G. (Box-folder 35/4)
    - Mostazo [-Morales], Juan
      - Coplas. Paris: Éditions espagnoles J. Garzón, 1936., Small orchestra; parts for: piano/conductor (containing chordal indications; vocal line indications in Spanish) (condensed score; 3 p.); vn I (2 p.); vc/tbn-cb, sax I (alto)-sax II (tenor), sax III (alto), tpt, perc, banjo (1 p. each).; Plate no. 1801.; On verso of each part: corresponding instrumental part for Bonaterra, Luis. La festa de la rambla All Mostazo material is included with the Bonaterra material (Box 8, Folder 2). (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Mozart, [Johann Chrysostom] Wolfgang Amadeus
      - Sonates. Paris: E. Gallet, n.d., Solo piano; score; 296 p.; Plate no. E.G.7708.; Contains annotations in pencil on contents page. (Box-folder 35/5)
      - Sechs deutsche Tänze. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Arranged by O. Taubmann for solo piano; score; 10 p.; Plate no. E.B.5374/24668. (Box-folder 35/6)
      - Divertimento, K. 205. Leipzig: E. Eulenburg, n.d., Miniature score; 20 p.; Plate no. E.E.1241. (Box-folder 35/7)
      - Divertimento, K. 247. Leipzig: E. Eulenburg, n.d., Miniature score; 31 p.; Plate no. E.E.1295. (Box-folder 35/8)
      - Divertimento, K. 334. Leipzig: E. Eulenburg, n.d., Miniature score; 50 p.; Plate no. E.E.1172. (Box-folder 35/9)
      - Don Giovanni, K. 527. London: Novello, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 299 p.; Language note: English; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 36/1)
      - Dorfmusikanten Sextett, K. 522. Leipzig: E. Eulenburg, n.d., Miniature score; 26 p.; Plate no. E.E.1317. (Box-folder 36/2)
      - Galimathias Musicum, K. 32. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Full score; 14 p.; Plate no. B.318. (Box-folder 36/3)
      - Idomeneo. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 295 p.; Plate no. V.A.202.; Language note: Italian; Language note: German (Box-folder 36/4)
      - Serenade, K. 361. Leipzig: E. Eulenburg, n.d., Miniature score; 78 p.; Plate no. E.E.1200. (Box-folder 36/5)
      - Serenade, K. 375. Leipzig: E. Eulenburg, n.d., Miniature score; 50 p.; Plate no. E.E.3320. (Box-folder 36/6)
      - Serenade, K. 388. Leipzig: E. Eulenburg, n.d., Miniature score; 40 p.; Plate no. E.E.3321. (Box-folder 36/7)
      - Türkischer Marsch. [Sonata, K. 300i (331), A major: Türkischer Marsch.] Leipzig: Anton J. Benjamin, n.d., Arranged by L. Weninger; part only for piano/conductor (condensed score); 4 p.; Plate no. A.J.B.7325.; Contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 36/8)
    - Musorgskiĭ, Modest Petrovich
      - Au village. [=V derevnie.] Moscow: P. Jurgenson, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 10552. (Box-folder 37/1)
      - Aux bords du Don. [=Po nad Donom sad tsvietet.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 5945.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 37/2)
      - Bez solntsa. [=Sans soleil; Sunless.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 27 p.; Plate no. 5950 through 5955.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 37/3)
      - Bilder einer Ausstellung. [=Pictures at an exhibition.] Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, n.d., Solo piano; score; 45 p.; Plate no. 31361. (Box-folder 37/4)
      - Boris Godunov. St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Piano-vocal score; 293 p.; Plate no. 6452.; Language note: Russian; Language note: French (Box-folder 37/5)
      - Boris Godunov [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Chorus parts (SAB only); 6 p.; 4 p.; 2 p.; Chorus parts (SAB only) for the Prologue's Coronation Scene.; Contains sparse performance indications. (Box-folder 37/6)
      - Un brave ne doit point filer. [=Oĭ chest'-li to molodtsu len priasti?] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 5942.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 37/7)
      - Chanson d'enfant. [=Dietskaia piesenka.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 5928.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 37/8)
      - Zwei Clavierstücke: Intermezzo. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 306. (Box-folder 37/9)
      - La couturière. [=Shveia.] Moscow: P. Jurgenson, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 10549. (Box-folder 37/10)
      - Dietskaia. [=The Nursery.] St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', n.d. See also: Enfantines, Box 37, Folder 14, Voice and piano; score; 42 p.; Plate no. 1452.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 37/11)
      - En Crimée (Capriccio). [=Bliz iuzhnago berega Kryma.] Moscow: P. Jurgenson, 1896., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 10550. (Box-folder 37/12)
      - En Crimée (Hoursouff-Notes de voyage). [=Na iuzhnom beregu Kryma.] Moscow: P. Jurgenson, 1896., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 10551. (Box-folder 37/13)
      - Enfantines. [=Dietskaia; The nursery.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908. See also: Dietskaia, Box 37, Folder 11, Voice and piano; score; 48 p.; Plate no. 5953.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 37/14)
      - L'errant. [=Strannik; The wanderer.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 5949.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 37/15)
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi See also: Sorochinskaia iarmarka
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi. [=Sorochinskaia iarmarka; Sorochintsy fair.] Petrograd: W. Bessel, 1923. See also: Sorochinskaia iarmarka, Piano-vocal score; 190 p.; Plate no. 8063.; Contains inscription to Diaghilev from A. and V. Bessel', on inside front cover page, identifying this score as a first edition; in Russian; in ink; dated "Paris, 1929."; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/47)
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi: Chanson de Khivria. [=Piesnia Khivri; Khivria's song.] Petrograd: W. Bessel, 1909., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 1900.; Published 1909/1921; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 37/16)
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi: Chanson de Khivria. St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 1900.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 37/17)
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi: Chanson de Parassia. [=Dumka Parasi; Parassia's song.] Petrograd: W. Bessel, 1908., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 1899.; Published 1908/1921; Language note: French; Language note: English; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 37/18)
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi: Chanson du jeune villageois. [=Dumka parobka.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908. See also: La foire de Sorotchintsi: Rêverie du jeune villageois, Box 38, Folder 5., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 5412.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 37/19)
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi: Gopak. St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', n.d., Arranged for full orchestra; full score; 15 p.; Plate no. 5403.; Contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 38/1)
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi: Gopak. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1898., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 8 p.; Plate no. 1157 1160.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 38/2)